Guide to the John C. Walker Texas Counties Collection
University of Houston Libraries
John C. Walker Texas Counties Collection
1818-1907
05/1969-040
3.00 linear feet
University of Houston Libraries
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains legal documents, advertisements, correspondence, and maps from various Texas counties dating from 1818 to 1907. Deeds and tax receipts make up a signififcant portion of the collection.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Advertisements; Correspondence; Deeds -- Texas; Legal documents; Maps (documents); Receipts (financial records)
Geographic Name:
Texas -- History
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
This collection contains legal documents, advertisements, correspondence, and maps from various Texas counties dating from 1818 to 1907. Deeds and tax receipts make up a signififcant portion of the collection. Counties represented include Angelina, Cherokee, Tyler, Nacogdoches, Brazoria, Fort Bend, Galveston, and Harris. Documents from the Republic of Texas are also included.
Detailed List of Contents
- Angelina County
  - Land for sale, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Advertisement
  - Deeds, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Legal Document
  - Description of head rights, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Property rights affidavit, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - De La Garza land grant, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Map
  - John Durst grant, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Land plat, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Deed of partition, November 28, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Deed, November 13, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Deed, November 14, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Deed of relinquishment, July 16, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Deed, land office copy, receipt, February 28, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Receipt, March 2, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Deed, January 20, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Lease agreement, January 20, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Land grant, August 9, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Deeds, December 8, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Deed, ? 28, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Deed, April 28, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Deed, December 28, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Deed, October 9, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Deed, April 22, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Deed, August 2, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Deed of sale, September 30, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Deeds, Dec. 27, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Deeds, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Deed of relinquishment, May 22, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Order to convey deed, December 6, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - W. L. Du...?, August 13, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Correspondence
  - Land grant, April 22, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Field notes, description, valuation, March 1887 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - John Durst, April 27, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Deeds, June 1, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Joseph Spence, July 25, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notice of interrogatories, December 14, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notice to serve cause, December 14, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Judgement of discontinuance, December 30, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tax statement, December 27, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tax receipt, January 5, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tax statements, January 7, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - John Durst, March 21, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Deed, March 21, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Tax receipt, January 31, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Tax receipt, March 2, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - John H. Walker, May 30, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Angelina & Cherokee County
  - J. F. Davis, August 9, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Jesus De La Garza 4th league, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Deed, August 15, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Petition, answer, cross petition, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Petition, September 4, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Draft of order of dismissal, December 30, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Special warranty deed, December 30, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - R. L. Henry, January 29, 1899? (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - John H. Walker, May 4 & 7, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Angelina, Cherokee & Tyler County
  - Quit claim deed, August 15, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Angelina & Nacogdoches County
  - Deed, February 28, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Bond, May 18, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Deed, June 1, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Brazoria County
  - Miscellaneous Documents, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Deeds, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Abstract of title, September 9, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Deeds, October 1, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Note w/vendor lien, October 1, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Notarized minutes of meeting, October 10, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Receipt, December 18, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Receipt, January 3, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Lease agreement, May 29, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Deed of sale, September 29, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tax receipt, April 9, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Tax receipt, November 23, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Quit claim deed, January 13, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - M. L. Robbins, December 30, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Tax receipts, March 30, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Release of vendor lien, September 21, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Deed of trust, October 8, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Tax receipts, April 4, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Receipt for survey, July 8, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Receipt, survey, August 17, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Tax statement, October 9, 1895 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Tax receipts, January 24, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Certificates of redemption, January 25, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Tax receipts, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Tax receipts, January 24, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Legal Documents
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Tax receipts, January 13, 1899 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Tax receipt, February 8, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Tax receipts, February 4, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Tax receipts, February 18, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Tax receipts, February 9, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Tax receipts, January 4, 1904 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Brazoria, Fort Bend, Galveston & Harris County
  - Land of the Galveston & Brazoria Land & Live Stock Company, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Galveston County
  - Misc. Documents, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Deed, January 18, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Deed of Trust, Promissory, May 20, 1872 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Release, July 11, 1872 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Deed, April 1, 1874 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - D. M. Murchison, July 27, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mutual discharge of each other, August 14, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Certified copy of judgement, June 5, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Promissory note, July 13, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Receipt, November 8, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Receipt, September 20, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Deeds, September 29, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Deed, October 13, 1882 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Deed, marked paid, March 23, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Deed, May 26, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - John Durst, August 15, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Building contract, November 21, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Memorandum of lease, December 9, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Legal Document, January 5, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Note marked paid
  - Mortgage for improvements, January 8, 1884 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Abstract of title, December 26, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Deed release, December 29, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Map, receipt, survey, May 3, 1886 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - H. M. Trueheart, May 14, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Lease agreement, January 1, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Deed, June 7, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - John C. Walker, August 5, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Deed, October 29, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Disclaimer, December 6, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Statement of account, December 19, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Earnest receipt, February 12, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Quit-claim deed, February 16, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Deed, March 6, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - L. R. Bergeron, November 11, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Receipt, December 22, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Abstract of title, August 29, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - James R. Burnet, October 14, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Special warranty deed, March 17, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Trustees deed, June 5, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Release, August 31, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Quit-claim deed, November 7, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - John A. Oliphant, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Nacogdoches County
  - Temporary map, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Deed of sale, January 20, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Legal document
  - Deed, April 1, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Deed, May 20, 1847? (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Deed, February 29, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Deed, September 29, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Promissory note, February 28, 1850 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Deed, January ?, 1851 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Deed, September 1, 1851 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Release of house & lot, December 2, 1851 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Deed, November 30, 1853 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Deeds, August 5, 1857 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - John C. Walker, August 28, 1857 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Deed, June 19, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Deed, August 10, 1859 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Deed, May 17, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Deed, September 1, 1868 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Deed, March 4, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Tax receipts, March 3,1874 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Tax receipts, December 27, 1879 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Tax receipts, December 16, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Tax receipts, January 25/26, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Tax receipts, January 27, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Tax receipts, December 2, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Tax receipts, December 21, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Tax receipts, January 30, 1886 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Contract of rent, November 9, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - James S. Upshaw, August 6, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Deeds, June 1, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Map & deed of declaration of streets, September 8, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Legal document/Map
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - F. C. Ford, January 19, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Tax receipt, December 30, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Tax receipt, January 27, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Other Counties
  - Harris County
    - Deed, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Cash & Luckell, Real Estate, April 1, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Tax receipt, June 12, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Haskell County
    - A. C. Foster, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Frederick Longfellow, April 1897 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - A. C. Foster, May 17, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Milam County
    - Warranty deed, September 29, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Nolan County
    - Misc. Documents, January 1898 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Polk County
    - Deed, March 12, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Release, August 1, 1871 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Republic of Texas
  - Legal Document (Spanish), 1818 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Deed (?), 1827-1831 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Deed, May 2, 1835 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Deed, March 20, 1837 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Deed, December 28, 1838 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Deed, January 21, 1839 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Land grant, August 2, 1839 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Deed, May 2, 1839 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Deed, October 12, 1840 (?) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Deed of sale, November 7, 1840 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Deed, May 28, 1842 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Deed, May 30, 1842 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Deed, August 5, 1842 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Power of attorney, August 20, 1842 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Deed, September 13, 1842 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Deed, June 17, 1843 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Transcript of execution, levy & sale, December 5, 1843 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Deed, December 15, 1843 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Transfer of certificate, June 4, 1844 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Deed, May 13, 1845 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Deed, September 18, 1845 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Deed, October 9, 1845 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Deed, October 19, 1845 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Deed of sale, November 25, 1845 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Deed, October 19, 1846 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1848 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1850 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1857 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 1863 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1881 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 1882 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - ​1883 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 1888 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 1890 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 1893 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 1894 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 1895 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 1896 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 1898 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 1904 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Miscellaneous Legal Documents
  - undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 1847 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 1852 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 1853 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 1854 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 1856 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 1858 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - 1859 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 1865 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - 1866 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - 1886 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - 1890 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - 1891 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - 1892 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - 1899 (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous
  - Miscellaneous documents, Miscellaneous dates (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Recording discs and typed transcription (Box 8, Item 1-2)
  - 3 Framed photographs (Box 8, Item 3-5)